I want to talk to you about,
أودّ أن أحدّثكم عن،
or share with you, a breakthrough new approach
بل أشارككم أسلوبًا جديدًا ومبتكرًا
for managing items of inventory inside of a warehouse.
لإدارة أصناف مخزّنة داخل أحد المستودعات.
We're talking about a pick, pack and ship setting here.
نتكلم عن الاختيار والتعليب والشحن.
sometimes thousands of mobile robots,
وأحيانًا الآلاف منهم،
moving around a warehouse. And I'll get to the solution.
متجولةً داخل المستودع وسوف أصل للحل.
But for a moment, just think
أمّا الآن،
about the last time that you ordered something online.
فكروا في آخر مرة اشتريتم شيئًا من على الإنترنت.
You were sitting on your couch
فها أنت جالس على الأريكة
and you decided that you absolutely had to have this red t-shirt.
ثم قررت شراء ذلك القميص الأحمر.
So — click! — you put it into your shopping cart.
فنقرت على الموقع الألكتروني وأضفته إلى مشترياتك.
And then you decided that green pair of pants
ثم وجدت ذلك السروال الأخضر الجميل.
looks pretty good too — click!
فنقرت مرة أخرى!
And maybe a blue pair of shoes — click!
وأيضًا ذلك الحذاء الأزرق فنقرت أخرى!
So at this point you've assembled your order.
إذًا حتى هذه المرحلة قمت بتجميع طلبيتك.
You didn't stop to think for a moment that
حتى أنك لم تفكّر للحظة
that might not be a great outfit.
أنها قد لا تلائمك كثيًرا.
But you hit "submit order."
ولكن نقرت على الفور "تقديم الطلب."
And two days later, this package shows up on your doorstep.
وبعد يومين، تصل هذه الطلبية إلى عتبة بابك
And you open the box and you're like, wow, there's my goo.
وتفتح الصندوق وتفرح لوصول حاجياتك.
Did you ever stop to think about how those items of inventory
هل توقفت للحظة وفكرت كيف تمكنت المواد المخزّنه هذه
actually found their way inside that box in the warehouse?
من الوصول إلى داخل هذا الصندوق في المستودع؟
So I'm here to tell you it's that guy right there.
أنا هنا لأخبركم أن هناك شخص حاليًا.
So deep in the middle of that picture,
في عمق منتصف هذه الصورة،
you see a classic pick-pack worker
ترون عمال التعليب النمطيين
in a distribution or order fulfillments setting.
في منطفة التوزيع أو تلبية الطلبات.
Classically these pick workers will spend 60 or 70 percent of their day
بشكل اعتيادي يقضي هؤلاء العمال 60 أو 70 بالمئة من يومهم
wandering around the warehouse.
يتجولون في أنحاء المستودع.
They'll often walk as much as 5 or 10 miles
غالبًا ما يمشون ما يقرب من 5 أو 10 أميال
in pursuit of those items of inventory.
خلال سعيهم وراء تلك المواد المخزّنة.
Not only is this an unproductive way to fill orders,
هذه الوسيلة ليست فقط غير مجدية لتعبئة الطلبات،
it also turns out to be an unfulfilling way to fill orders.
اتضح أيضًا أنها وسيلة لا تلبي الطلبات.
So let me tell you where I first bumped into this problem.
اسمحوا لي أن أخبركم أين اصطدمت بهذه المشكلة أول مرة.
I was out in the Bay area in '99, 2000, the dot com boom.
كنت في منطقة الخليج في عامي 1999 و 2000 أثناء ازدهار الإنترنت.
I worked for a fabulously spectacular flame-out called Webvan.
عملت لموقع مذهل خرافي السقوط يدعى (ويب فان).
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
This company raised hundreds of millions of dollars with the notion that
جمعت هذه الشركة ملايين الدولارات تحت شعار
we will deliver grocery orders online.
سوف نقوم بتسليم طلبات البقالة من خلال الإنترنت.
And it really came down to the fact that we couldn't do it cost effectively.
وتبين في الواقع أنه لا يمكننا أن نقوم بذلك بشكل فعّال من حيث التكلفة.
Turns out e-commerce was something that was very hard and very costly.
اتضح أن التجارة الإلكترونية كانت صعبة ومكلفة للغاية.
In this particular instance we were trying to assemble 30 items of inventory
في هذا المثال تحديدًا قد حاولنا جمع 30 مادة مخزّنة
into a few totes, onto a van to deliver to the home.
في بضع حقائب على شاحنة صغيرة لتسليمها للمنزل.
And when you think about it, it was costing us 30 dollars.
وعندما تفكرون بالأمر ستعرفون بأنها كانت تكلفنا 30 دولار.
Imagine, we had an 89¢ can of soup
تصوروا، كان لدينا علبة حساء بقيمة 89 سنت
that was costing us one dollar to pick and pack into that tote.
تكلفنا دولارًا لاختيارها وتعليبها داخل الحقيبة.
And that's before we actually tried to deliver it to the home.
هذا قبل أن نحاول فعليًا إيصالها إلى المنزل.
So long story short, during my one year at Webvan,
قصة طويلة باختصار، خلال سنة واحدة من العمل لدى ويبفان،
what I realized by talking to all the material-handling providers
ما أدركته من الحديث مع جميع مزوّدي المواد
was that there was no solution designed specifically to solve each base picking.
أنّه لا يوجد حل مصمم خصيصًا لكل قاعدة انتقاء.
Red item, green, blue, getting those three things in a box.
المادة الحمراء والخضراء والزرقاء رتب تلك الأشياء الثلاثة في صندوق.
So we said, there's just got to be a better way to do this.
لذلك قلنا، يجب أن يكون هناك طريقة أفضل للقيام بذلك.
Existing material handling was set up to pump
تم إنشاء منصات تجهيز الأصناف للضخ المتواجدة حاليًا
pallets and cases of goo to retail stores.
وأغلفة تعليب لمحلات البيع بالتجزئة.
Of course Webvan went out of business, and about a year and a half later,
بالطبع خرجت (ويبفان) من العمل وبعد حوالي عام وتصف،
I was still noodling on this problem. It was still nagging at me.
مازالت هذه المشكلة تؤرقني وتشغل تفكيري.
And I started thinking about it again.
وبدأت أفكر في الأمر مرةً أخرى.
And I said, let me just focus briefly on what I wanted as a pick worker,
وقلت، لأركّز فقط على ما أريده لو كنت عامل انتقاء،
or my vision for how it should work.
أو رؤيتي لكيف يجب أن تعمل.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I said, let's focus on the problem.
قلت، لأركّز على المشكلة.
I have an order here and what I want to do is I want to put
لدي طلبية هنا وما أريده هو أن أضع
red, green and blue in this box right here.
الأحمر والأخضر والأزرق في هذا الصندوق هنا.
What I need is a system where I put out my hand and — poof! —
ما أحتاجه هو نظام يمكنني من الإشارة بيدي فقط و ــ فجأة! ــ
the product shows up and I pack it into the order,
يظهر المنتج وأضيفه إلى الطلبية،
and now we're thinking,
ونحن الآن نفكر،
this would be a very operator-centric approach to solving the problem.
هذا سيكون أسلوب العامل المركزي لحل المشكلة.
This is what I need. What technology is available to solve this problem?
هذا ما أحتاجه، ما التكنولوجيا المتاحة لحلّ هذه المشكلة؟
But as you can see, orders can come and go, products can come and go.
ولكن كما تشاهدون، الطلبيات يمكن أن تأتي وتذهب، المنتجات يمكن أن تأتي وتذهب.
It allows us to focus on making the pick worker the center of the problem,
ذلك يمكننا من التركيز لجعل عامل الاختيار محور المشكلة،
and providing them the tools to make them as productive as possible.
وتزويدهم بالأدوات لجعلهم منتجين قدر الإمكان.
So how did I arrive at this notion?
إذًا كيف توصلت إلى هذه الفكرة؟
Well, actually it came from a brainstorming exercise,
حسنًا، في الواقع نتج هذا من تمرين لاستثارة الأفكار،
probably a technique that many of you use,
تقريبًا التقنية التي يستخدمها الكثير منكم،
It's this notion of testing your ideas.
هي فكرة اختبار أفكاركم.
Take a blank sheet, of course,
خذ ورقة فارغة، بالطبع،
but then test your ideas at the limits — infinity, zero.
ولكن بعد ذلك اختبر أفكارك في حدود ــ ما لا نهاية، صفر.
In this particular case, we challenged ourselves with the idea:
في هذه الحالة بالذات، تحدينا أنفسنا بفكرة:
What if we had to build a distribution center in China,
ماذا لو اضطررنا لبناء مركز توزيع في الصين،
where it's a very, very low-cost market?
حيث السوق منخفض التكلفة؟
And say, labor is cheap, land is cheap.
وكما يقال، عندما تكون اليد العاملة رخيصة تكون الأرض رخيصة.
And we said specifically,
ونقول بالتحديد،
"What if it was zero dollars an hour for direct labor
"ماذا لو كانت تكلفة العامل صفر من الدولارات في الساعة
and we could build a million- square-foot distribution center?"
وتمكننا من بناء مركز توزيع بمساحة مليون متر مربع؟"
So naturally that led to ideas that said,
إذًا طبيعي أن يقودنا هذا للأفكار التي قالت،
"Let's put lots of people in the warehouse."
"لنضع الكثير من الأشخاص في المستودع."
And I said, "Hold on, zero dollars per hour,
وقلت، "تمهلوا، صفر من الدولارات في الساعة،
what I would do is 'hire'
ما أود فعله هو "توظيف"
10,000 workers to come to the warehouse every morning at 8 a.m.,
عشرة آلاف عامل ليأتوا للمستودع كل صباح في الثامنة،
walk into the warehouse and pick up one item of inventory
يتجولون في المستودع ويختارون صنف واحد
and then just stand there.
ويقفون هناك فقط.
So you hold Captain Crunch, you hold the Mountain Dew,
إذًا أنت التزم بكابتن كرنش، وأنت التزم بماونتن ديو،
you hold the Diet Coke.
وأنت التزم بدايت كولا.
If I need it, I'll call you, otherwise just stand there.
إذا احتجته، سأطلبك عدا عن ذلك إبق واقفًا هناك.
But when I need Diet Coke and I call it, you guys talk amongst yourselves.
ولكن عندما أحتاج دايت كولا وأطلبها، تكلموا فيما بينكم أبها الفتية.
Diet Coke walks up to the front — pick it, put it in the tote, away it goes."
يأتي المسؤول عن دايت كولا إلى المقدمة ـ يختاره ويضعه في الحقيبة وتنطلق الطلبية."
Wow, what if the products could walk and talk on their own?
رائع، ماذا لو تمكّن المنتج من المشي والتحدث بنفسه؟
That's a very interesting, very powerful way
هذا مثير للاهتمام جدًا أسلوب فعّال جدًا
that we could potentially organize this warehouse.
يمكنه تنظيم هذا المستودع.
So of course, labor isn't free,
بالطبع، العمالة ليست مجانية،
on that practical versus awesome spectrum.
على ذلك العملي مقابل الطيف المدهش.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So we said mobile shelving — We'll put them on mobile shelving.
لذا اقترحنا الرفوف المتحركة ــ سنضعهم على رفوف متحركة.
We'll use mobile robots and we'll move the inventory around.
سنستخدم روبوتات متحركة وسنحرك السلع المخزّنة حولها.
And so we got underway on that and then I'm sitting on my couch in 2008.
لذا بدأنا بذلك ثم أجلس على أريكتي في 2008.
Did any of you see the Beijing Olympics, the opening ceremonies?
هل شاهد أحد منكم أولمبياد بكّين، حفل الافتتاح؟
I about fell out of my couch when I saw this.
كنت على وشك الوقوع من على أريكتي عندما شاهدت هذا.
I'm like, that was the idea!
أنا كما، كانت تلك هي الفكرة!
(Laughter and Applause)
(ضحك وتصفيق)
We'll put thousands of people on the warehouse floor, the stadium floor.
سنضع آلاف الأشخاص على أرض المستودع، أرض الإستاد.
But interestingly enough, this actually relates to the idea
ومما يثير الإهتمام، هذه تتعلق بالفكرة
in that these guys were creating some incredibly powerful, impressive digital art,
من حيث أنّ هؤلاء الأشخاص كانو يصنعون فنًا رقميًا مثيرًا للإعجاب وضخمًا بشكل لايصدّق.
all without computers, I'm told,
كل هذا دون كمبيوتر كما قيل لي،
it was all peer-to-peer coordination and communication.
كل شيء تمّ بتنسيق واتصالات بنظام النظير إلى النظير.
You stand up, I'll squat down.
أنت تقف وأنا سأجلس القرفصاء.
And they made some fabulous art.
لقد قاموا يعمل فنّي رائع.
It speaks to the power of emergence
يتحدث إلى قوة البزوغ
in systems when you let things start to talk with each other.
في أنظمة تسمح للأشياء فيها أن تتحدّث مع بعضها.
So that was a little bit of the journey.
كان هذا جزءً يسيرًا من الرحلة.
So of course, now what became the practical reality of this idea?
إذًا بالطبع، الآن ما أصبح واقع عملي لهذه الفكرة؟
Here is a warehouse.
هنا مستودع.
It's a pick, pack and ship center that has about 10,000 different SKUs.
هو مركز الاختيار والتعليب والشحن يحتوي حوالي عشرة آلاف وحدة تخزين مختلفة.
We'll call them red pens, green pens, yellow Post-It Notes.
سندعوهم الأفلام الحمراء والخضراء ولصاقات الملحوظات الصفراء.
We send the little orange robots out to pick up the blue shelving pods.
نرسل الروبوتات البرتقالية الصغيرة لالتقاط الرفوف الزرقاء.
And we deliver them to the side of the building.
ونسلمهم إلى جانب المبنى.
So all the pick workers now get to stay on the perimeter.
لذلك على كل عمال الانتقاء أن يتواجدوا في المحيط.
And the game here is to pick up the shelves,
واللعبة هنا هي التقاط الرفوف،
take them down the highway and deliver them straight to the pick worker.
ثم أخذها على طول الطريق السريع وتسليمها مباشرة إلى العامل.
This pick worker's life is completely different.
حياة العامل مختلفة تمامًا.
Rather than wandering around the warehouse, she gets to stay still
بدلًا من التجوال في أنحاء المستودع، ما عليها إلا البقاء
in a pick station like this
في محطة انتقاء مثل هذه
and every product in the building can now come to her.
ويمكن لكل المنتجات الآن في المبنى أن تصل إليها.
So the process is very productive.
إذًا العملية منتجة جدًا.
Reach in, pick an item, scan the bar code, pack it out.
تدخل وتختار منتج ما وتمسح شريط الرموز وتعلّب.
By the time you turn around,
وقبل أن تلتفت،
there's another product there ready to be picked and packed.
هناك منتج آخر جاهز للاختيار والتعليب.
So what we've done is take out all of the non-value added
إذاً ما قمنا به هو أننا تخلصنا مماليس له قيمة
walking, searching, wasting, waited time,
من أوقات التجوال والبحث والضياع والانتظار،
and we've developed a very high-fidelity way to pick these orders,
وقمنا بتطوير طريقة عالية الدقة لالتقاط هذه الطلبيات،
where you point at it with a laser, scan the UPC barcode,
حيث تشير إليها بالليزر وتمسح شريط الرموز،
and then indicate with a light which box it needs to go into.
ثم تشير بالضوء إلى الصندوق الذي تريد الوصول إليه.
So more productive, more accurate and, it turns out,
إذًا أكثر إنتاجية‘ وأكثر دقة، وتبيّن،
it's a more interesting office environment for these pick workers.
أنها بيئة مكتبية أكثر متعة لهؤلاء العمال.
They actually complete the whole order.
هم بالفعل يكملون الطلبية بأكملها.
So they do red, green and blue, not just a part of the order.
إذًا هم يشيرون بالأحمر والأخضر والأزرق ليس فقط كجزء من الطلبية
So the side effects of this approach
إذًا الآثار الجانبية لهذه الطريقة
are what really surprised us.
هي التي أثارت دهشتنا.
We knew it was going to be more productive.
علمنا بأنها ستكون أكثر إنتاجية.
But we didn't realize just how pervasive this way of thinking
لكننا لم ندرك فقط كيفية انتشار طريقة التفكر هذه
extended to other functions in the warehouse.
امتدادها لوظائف أخرى في المستودع.
But what effectively this approach is doing inside of the DC
ولكن إن ما تقوم به هذه الطريقة بفاعلية داخل العاصمة
is turning it into a massively parallel processing engine.
هو تحويلها إلى محرك معالجة موازٍ ذو نطاق واسع.
So this is again a cross-fertilization of ideas.
إذًا مرة أخرى تلاقح أفكار مرة أخرى.
Here's a warehouse and we're thinking about
هنا مستودع ونحن نفكر به
parallel processing supercomputer architectures.
أبنية معالجة موازية عملاقة.
The notion here is that you have
الفكرة هنا أن يكون لديكم
10 workers on the right side of the screen
عشرة عمال على الجانب الأيمن من الشاشة
If the worker in station three decides to leave and go to the bathroom,
ففي حال قرر العامل في المحطة 3 المغادرة والذهاب إلى الحمام،
it has no impact on the productivity of the other nine workers.
لن يكون لذلك أثر على إنتاجية باقي العمال التسعة.
Contrast that, for a moment, with the traditional method of using a conveyor.
على النقيض من ذلك يحدث مع الطريقة التقليدية عند استخدام الناقل.
When one person passes the order to you,
عندما يمرر شخص واحد الطلبية إليك،
you put something in and pass it downstream.
تضع شيءً ما وتمرره نحو الأسفل.
Everyone has to be in place for that serial process to work.
على الجميع التزام أماكنهم لتجرى عملية العمل التسلسلية.
This becomes a more robust way to think about the warehouse.
لتصبح هذه الطريقة الأكثر قوةً في التعامل مع المستودع.
And then underneath the hoods gets interesting in that we're tracking
ثم يصبح أكثر إثارة تحت الأغطية من حيث أننا نتتبّع
the popularity of the products.
شعبية المنتجات.
And we're using dynamic and adaptive algorithms
باستخدامنا لخوارزميات ديناميكية وقابلة للتكيف
to tune the floor of the warehouse.
لضبط أرضية المستودع.
So what you see here potentially the week leading up to Valentine's Day.
لذلك ما تراه هنا من المحتمل أن يكون الأسبوع الذي يسبق عيد الحب.
All that pink chalky candy has moved to the front of the building
لقد تم نقل كل الحلوى الطباشيرية الوردية إلى الجزء الأمامي من المبنى
and is now being picked into a lot of orders in those pick stations.
والآن يتم انتقاؤها من أجل الكثير من الطلبيات في إحدى المحطات.
Come in two days after Valentine's Day, and that candy, the leftover candy,
تعال بعد يومين من عيد الحب وستجد كل الحلويات، أو ما تبقى منها،
has all drifted to the back of the warehouse
فد تم نقلها إلى مؤخرة المخزن
and is occupying the cooler zone on the thermal map there.
وتشغل المنطقة الأبرد من الخريطة الحرارية للمستودع.
One other side effect of this approach using the parallel processing
إحدى الآثار الجانبية الأخرى للمعالجة الموازية
is these things can scale to ginormous.
هو هل بإمكان هذه الأشياء تحجيم الأصناف الضخمة
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So whether you're doing two pick stations, 20 pick stations,
لذلك سواء إذا كنت تقوم بمحطتين اختيار، أو عشرين محطة،
or 200 pick stations, the path planning algorithms
أو مئتين محطة، فإنّ خوارزميات تخطيط المسار
and all of the inventory algorithms just work.
وجميع خوارزميات الجرد تعمل بشكل جيد.
In this example you see that the inventory
في هذا المثال تشاهدون أن المخزون
has now occupied all the perimeter of the building
قد احتل كل محيط المبنى
because that's where the pick stations were.
لأنه في المكان حيث محطات الاختيار.
They sorted it out for themselves.
فرزوها لأنفسهم.
So I'll conclude with just one final video
سوف أختم فقط بفيديو نهائي واحد
that shows how this comes to bear
يظهر الأثر
on the pick worker's actual day in the life of.
في يوم فعلي لعامل انتقاء.
So as we mentioned, the process is to move inventory along the highway
إذًا كما ذكرنا، العملية هي أن ننقل المخزون على طول الممر السريع
and then find your way into these pick stations.
ثم إيجاد الطريق إلى محطات الانتقاء تلك.
And our software in the background
وبرامجنا في الخلفية
understands what's going on in each station,
تفهم ما يحدث في كل محطة،
we direct the pods across the highway
نحن نوجه العربات عبر الممر السريع
and we're attempting to get into a queuing system
ونحاول الوصول إلى نظام الطابور
to present the work to the pick worker.
لتقديم العمل إلى عامل الانتقاء.
What's interesting is we can even adapt the speed of the pick workers.
المثير للإهتمام هو أننا يمكننا أيضًا التحكّم بسرعة عمال الإختيار.
The faster pickers get more pods and the slower pickers get few.
فالعامل الأسرع يصله عربات أكثر والأبطأ يصله أقل.
But this pick worker now is literally having that experience
لكن لدى هؤلاء العمال الآن تلك التجربة حرفيًا
that we described before.
التي شرحناها من قبل.
She puts out her hand. The product jumps into it.
ترفع يدها ويقفز المنتج داخلها.
Or she has to reach in and get it.
أو ترفع يدها لتصل إليه.
She scans it and she puts it in the bucket.
تمسحه رقميًا وتضعه في السلة.
And all of the rest of the technology is kind of behind the scenes.
أما باقي مراحل التكنولوجيا تبقى خلف الكواليس.
So she gets to now focus on the picking and packing portion of her job.
لذلك لديها الآن الفرصة لتركز على الانتقاء والتعليب.
Never has any idle time, never has to leave her mat.
لن يكون لديها وقت أبدًا للكسل، لن يكون عليها أبدًا مغادرة بساطها.
And actually we think not only a more productive
في الحقيقة نحن لا نسعى فقط لإنتاجية أكبر
and more accurate way to fill orders.
وطريقة ذات دقة أعلى لملىء الطلبيات.
We think it's a more fulfilling way to fill orders.
نحن نعتقد أنها وسيلة أكثر إنجازًا لتلبية الطلبيات.
The reason we can say that, though, is that workers
السبب الذي يمكننا قوله، أن العمال الآن
in a lot of these buildings now compete
في الكثير من هذه المباني يتنافسون
for the privilege of working in the Kiva zone that day.
لنيل الإمتياز والعمل في المنطقة (كيفا) في ذلك اليوم.
And sometimes we'll catch them on testimonial videos
وسوف نضبطهم أحيانًا في أحد فيديوهات الأدلة
saying such things as,
يقولون أشياءً مثل،
they have more energy after the day to play with their grandchildren,
"لديهه طاقة أكبر بعد يوم العمل للعب مع أحفادهم،
or in one case a guy said, "the Kiva zone is so stress-free
أو في مثال آخر أحدهم يقول: "إن منطقة (كيفا) خالية من الضغط
that I've actually stopped taking my blood pressure medication."
إلى حد أنني توقفت من تناول دواء ضغط الدم"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
That was at a pharmaceutical distributor, so they told us not to use that video.
وكان ذلك موزع أدوية، لذلك قالوا لنا لا تستخدموا هذا الفيديو.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So what I wanted to leave you with today is the notion that
ما أريدكم أن أترككم معه اليوم هو فكرة أنكم
when you let things start to think and walk
إذا تركتم الأشياء تفكّر وتمشي
and talk on their own, interesting processes and productivities can emerge.
وتتحدّث وحدها، ستنشأ عمليات وانتاجيات مدهشة.
And now I think next time you go to your front step
والآن أعتقد أنكم المرة القادمة تذهبون إلى عتبة بابكم
and pick up that box that you just ordered online,
وتلتقطون الصندوق الذي طلبتوه للتو،
you break it open and the goo is in there,
وتفتحوه، وإذ بأغراضكم داخله،
you'll have some wonderment as to whether a robot
ستتساءلون إذا ما كان الروبوت
assisted in the picking and packing of that order.
قد ساعد في انتقاء وتعليب طلبكم.
Thank you.
شكرًا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)